Bill Crawford Papers
Bill Crawford Papers
1949-1968
Crawford, Bill, 1913-1982
9.67 linear ft.
709 editorial cartoons drawn for the Newark News and the Newspaper Enterprise Association and 5 magazine illustrations.
148914
Biographical History
Bill Crawford (1913-1982) was an award-winning American editorial cartoonist.
William “Bill” Crawford was born on March 18, 1913 and grew up in Hammond, Indiana. His father, a banker, encouraged him to be serious about drawing and Crawford won a cartoon contest as a high school student in Cleveland, Ohio. Crawford studied fine art and sculpture at Ohio State University where he edited the comic magazine Sun Dial, and after receiving a B.A. in 1935, went abroad to study painting and drawing in Paris at the Grand Chaumiere.
Originally a sports cartoonist, Crawford worked at the Washington Post and the Washington Daily News from 1936 to 1938 before joining the Newark News. Crawford defended powerful cartoons that took strong positions. In March 1962, he left for the Newspaper Enterprise Association, replacing John Fischetti as chief editorial cartoonist. Although his cartoons were widely reprinted while with the Newark News, Crawford’s cartoons were distributed to over 700 newspapers in the United States and Canada through the NEA until Crawford’s retirement in 1977.
Crawford was active with the National Cartoonists Society, serving as president from 1960 to 1961. He was named NCS best editorial cartoonist four times (1956-1958, 1966) and received the Silver T-Square award in 1973. Crawford, also a sculptor, created the NCS Reuben award sculpture. In 1970, the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists presented Crawford with the National Headliner Award.
Crawford’s gags and illustrations also appeared in national magazines; he illustrated 20 books and also taught at the Newark School of Fine and Industrial Arts and Rutgers University. In 1956 and 1959, Crawford toured with the U.S. State Department to entertain military forces in Germany and France.
Bill Crawford retired in 1977 and died of pneumonia at George Washington University Hospital in Washington D.C on January 6, 1982.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bill Crawford Papers consists of 2 series. Cartoons comprise the bulk of the collection with 602 original cartoons drawn for the Newark News and 107 original cartoons produced for the Newspaper Enterprise Association. The cartoons from the Newark News are undated but the NEA cartoons are from 1967 and 1968 but lack specific months and days. The undated cartoons span the period from approximately 1949 to 1962.
Crawford frequently depicted issues of interest to suburban Essex County, New Jersey including local New Jersey politics (as well as sometimes New York politics) and national and international affairs. Crawford used a copious amount of labels in his cartoons. Political contestants appear as squabbling children, and bewildered elephants and donkeys scour the landscape for voters. Rockets dubbed "Cost of Living" shoot out of sight, and automobiles named "Foreign Aid" chase vehicles called "Military Budget." Of particular interest is Crawford's portrayal of Nikita Khrushchev whom he often dubbed simply as "K".
The cartoons were drawn on Glarco illustration board with ink and crayon with captions appearing in blue pencil. Many of the cartoons feature heavy, dramatic shading and notations about their size and publication. Dimensions of the original art vary, however the majority are approximately 19"x 22". Several cartoons have captions that were crossed out and replaced with an alternative caption. Those cartoons have been filed under their original caption.
In addition to the inventory and index below, a partial inventory listing the captions of approximately 100 cartoons is also available at.
Also in the collection are 5 magazine illustrations. Three appeared in Life and also one in New Republic and one in Collier's. Crawford signed the drawing for New Republic as "Dale".
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged in a rough alphabetical fashion, located in folders for each letter of the alphabet.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Crawford, Bill, 1913-1982.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Newspaper Enterprise Association.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons; United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Newark evening news.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Caricatures and cartoons -- New Jersey.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoonists -- New Jersey.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- New Jersey -- Newark.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Peace -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Traffic fatalities -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government, 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Drawings (visual works); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Crawford, 1968-1970.
Inventory
- Editorial cartoons
  - Undated, circa 1949-1962
    - A, 20 items (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - A, 20 items (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - A, 20 items (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    - A, 9 items (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - B, 16 items (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
    - C, 13 items (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
    - C, 10 items (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    - D, 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
    - E, 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    - F, 18 items (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    - G, 8 items (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    - H, 15 items (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    - H, 13 items (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    - I, 16 items (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
    - I, 12 items (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
    - I, 16 items (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
    - J, 6 items (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
    - K, 4 items (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
    - L, 23 items (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
    - M, Hoover Commission cartoon is labeled May 21, 1955; 13 items (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
    - M, 12 items (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
    - N, 15 items (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
    - N, 15 items (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
    - O, 20 items (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
    - O, Einstein cartoon is labeled April 20, 1955; 14 items (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
    - P, one cartoon is labeled Jan 15, 1961; 11 items (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
    - R, 13 items (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
    - S, 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
    - S, 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
    - S, 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
    - T, 20 items (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
    - T, 20 items (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
    - T, 20 items (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
    - T, 20 items (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
    - T, 8 items (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
    - T, one cartoon is dated April 20, 1955; 21 items (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
    - U, 3 items (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
    - V, 4 items (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
    - W, 23 items (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
    - W, 22 items (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
    - Y, 13 items (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
    - untitled, 4 items (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - Dated
    - A-B, 1967; 17 items (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
    - C-D, F, H, 1967; 16 items (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
    - I-J, L, 1967; 16 items (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
    - N-P, 1967; 16 items (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
    - Q-S, 1967; 11 items (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
    - T, 1967; 10 items (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
    - V-Y, untitled, 1967; 10 items (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
    - A-B, M,-N, P, T, W, untitled, 1968; 11 items (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
- Magazine illustrations
  - Collier's - "The League Lives On" - skeleton holding a syringe labeled narcotics, 19 Dec (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - Life Magazine - Eino Felliikkinnenn (Ben Miller), undated (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - Life Magazine - Jack Williams, Pat Kingdon, Red Buttons, Ellen Hanley, undated (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - Life Magazine - Yetta and Noblese, Solen Burry, Nancy Walker, undated (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - New Republic - Rep. High Command #1, Senator Wherry (Just Call me Ken), undated; signed as "Dale" (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
22nd Amendment B1F2
Acheson, Dean B6F1-B6F2 B8F2
Adams, Sherman B5F5
AFL-CIO B4F3 B8F1
Africa B6F1
aeronautics B1F1 B3F1 B3F3-B3F4 B7F2 B9F3 B9F6
airplane crash B5F6 B7F1
Alabama B6F3 B8F5
Alaska B7F2
Algeria B2F5
anti-trust laws B4F3
armed forces B1F3 B4F3
Asia B1F1 B7F4 B8F7
Atlantic Pact B1F2 B2F3 B7F1 B8F4
auto industry B7F4 B9F5
automobile accidents B1F4 B2F2 B2F4 B4F4 B4F6 B5F2 B5F5 B6F2-B6F3 B7F5 B9F2 B9F6
Benson, Ezra Taft B7F3
Berlin B2F1 B3F1 B4F5 B5F1 B5F5-B6F1 B6F3-B6F5 B7F2 B7F4 B8F4 B8F6
Black Power B9F1
bossism B2F5 B8F6
Brandt, Willie B4F5
Brennan Jr., William J. B4F6
Britain B1F2 B2F3 B4F2 B4F5 B6F4 B9F4 B9F8
Brown, H. Rap B9F4
budget B1F2 B3F3 B7F3 B8F5
business B6F1 B6F5 B7F2 B9F3
Butler, Paul M. B2F2 B5F2 B5F5
California B1F1 B8F1
Cambodia B9F8
Carey, Dennis B2F1 B8F6
Carlin, Leo B4F6 B5F5
Castro, Fidel B1F3 B2F5 B4F2 B5F1-B5F3 B6F4-B6F5 B7F1 B8F4-B8F5 B8F7
charity B4F2 B8F1 B8F6
children B2F3
China B1F2-B1F3 B2F1-B2F2 B2F4 B3F3 B5F3 B6F2 B6F5 B7F4-B7F5 B8F4 B9F2 B9F4 B9F6
cities B9F5
civil rights B1F2 B3F3 B4F1 B4F5 B4F6 B5F2 B5F4 B5F6 B6F3-B6F4 B7F1-B7F3 B8F5 B9F1 B9F4
Civil War B8F5
coal industry B3F3
Cold War B7F4 B8F5
colonialism B5F4
common market B4F1 B9F1-B9F2
communism B2F1-B2F3 B3F1 B4F2 B4F4 B6F3 B8F1 B8F4 B9F4 B9F7
Congo B1F1 B2F1 B3F4 B5F6 B6F4 B9F1
Congress B1F1-B1F4 B2F2-B2F4 B3F1 B3F3-B4F1 B4F3-B4F4 B4F6 B5F2-B5F5 B6F1-B6F4 B7F1-B7F4 B8F1 B8F4-B8F5 B9F1-B9F3 B9F5-B9F8
cost of living B2F3 B3F4 B4F6 B5F2-B5F3 B8F5 B9F1 B9F5
counterculture B9F1 B9F6
Cuba B3F3 B4F1 B5F1 B8F4 B8F7
de Gaulle, Charles B1F2 B2F2 B2F5 B3F4 B4F3 B5F1 B7F3 B8F1 B9F1-B9F2 B9F4 B9F6
defense B1F1 B1F4 B2F1 B3F1 B4F2 B5F2 B9F6
democracy B3F1 B9F1-B9F3
Democratic Party B2F2 B2F4 B3F1 B3F3 B4F5 B5F2 B5F4-B5F5 B6F2-B6F4 B7F2-B7F4 B8F1 B8F5-B8F6
demonstrations B9F2-B9F3 B9F5
Dewey, Thomas B3F4 B6F1
dictatorships B2F2
diplomacy B4F6 B5F4 B8F4 B9F4
Dirksen, Everett B3F3 B5F4
disarmament B1F3-B1F4 B4F2 B4F6 B5F2 B5F6 B7F4
Dodd, Thomas J. B4F3 B9F1 B9F3
Dominican Republic B5F1
draft B9F1 B9F4 B9F7
Dulles, John Foster B2F3 B8F5
Durkin, Martin P. B2F5
Eastland, James B4F6
economy B3F2 B4F2 B4F6 B5F2-B5F3 B6F4 B7F4 B8F6 B9F1 B9F5 B9F7-B9F8
education B1F1-B1F2 B2F3 B6F3 B6F3 B8F5
Egypt B9F1
Eichmann, Adolph B4F4 B7F2 B7F5
Einstein, Albert B5F6
Eisenhower, Dwight B1F1-B1F4 B2F2-B2F4 B3F1-B3F4 B4F3 B4F6 B5F4-B5F5 B6F1-B6F2 B6F5-B7F2 B7F4-B8F1 B8F4 B8F7
Eisenhower, Mamie B2F1
elections B1F1 B2F3 B3F1 B3F3 B4F1 B4F6 B5F2-B5F4 B5F6 B7F1-B7F4 B8F1 B8F4-B8F5 B9F4 B9F8
electoral college B1F3
espionage B5F5 B7F4 B8F1
ethics B2F2 B3F1 B9F1-B9F3
Europe B2F2 B4F1 B5F4
fallout shelters B8F6
farmers B1F4 B6F5 B7F4
farming B8F4-B8F5
fashion B2F3
Faubus, Orval B7F3-B7F4
Federal Trade Commission B8F5
food prices B3F4
foreign aid B1F1 B1F4 B3F1 B5F3 B9F2
foreign policy B1F1 B2F3 B2F5 B6F2 B9F1
France B1F2 B2F3 B4F2 B4F5 B5F1 B6F5 B9F1 B9F4
Franco, Francisco B6F5
freedom B3F1
gambling B4F3 B7F2-B7F3
Germany B1F2 B3F1 B3F4 B8F4
gold reserve B9F8
Goldwater, Barry B2F1 B4F1 B4F3 B5F4
government regulation B4F1 B6F5
Greece B1F2 B9F4
Gromyko, Andrei B4F1 B5F4 B6F1 B8F6
gun lobby B9F3
Hall, Leonard B5F5 B8F7
Halleck, Charles B3F3 B4F1 B5F4
Hammarskjold, Dag B2F1 B5F6
Harriman, W. Averell B1F1-B1F2 B5F4
healthcare B2F4 B3F1 B5F1 B7F4 B9F4
birth rate B5F3
highway construction B5F6
Hitler, Adolph B3F3
Ho Chi Minh B9F3-B9F4 B9F7
Hoffa, Jimmy B1F2-B1F3 B2F5 B4F5-B4F6 B6F2 B7F2
holidays B1F1-B1F2 B1F4 B2F2-B2F3 B2F5 B5F5 B6F2-B6F3 B7F5 B9F1 B9F3 B9F6
Hoover, Hebert B6F1
Hoover Commission B5F1
housing B4F1 B7F4
Hughes, Richard B2F1 B2F4 B3F4 B5F2 B6F2-B6F3 B7F2 B8F1 B8F4 B8F6
Humphrey, Hubert B5F5 B6F4 B7F3
Hungary B3F1 B3F3 B7F4
India B2F4 B3F2
industry (general) B3F1 B8F4
inflation B2F2 B3F4 B8F4-B8F5 B9F1
integration B7F3
Iran B1F2
Iraq B9F1
Israel B9F2 B9F5
Japan B5F2
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B2F3 B3F2 B4F5 B5F5 B6F4 B7F3 B9F1-B9F8
judicial system B5F5
Kadar, Janos B3F3
Kennedy, John F. B1F1-B1F3 B2F3-B4F3 B4F5-B4F6 B5F2-B5F3 B5F5-B6F4 B7F1 B7F3 B8F1 B8F3-B8F4 B8F6
Kennedy, Robert F. B3F1 B9F7
Kenny, John J. B2F1 B2F5 B7F3 B8F1 B8F6
Khrushchev, Nikita B1F1 B1F3 B2F2 B2F4-B2F5 B3F3-B4F1 B4F3 B4F5-B5F3 B5F5-B6F4 B7F1-B7F3 B8F1-B8F7
King Jr., Martin Luther B9F6
Knight, William J. B1F1 B8F1
Knowland, William B1F1 B2F4 B8F1
Korea B3F1 B5F5 B9F1
Korean War B1F2 B2F1 B5F3 B6F4
Kosygin, Alexey B9F5 B9F7
labor B4F3 B5F2 B7F1 B9F3
Laos B1F1 B2F3-B2F5 B3F3 B4F3 B5F6 B6F3-B6F4 B8F4
Latin America B4F2 B8F3
law and order B9F3
Lie, Trygve B1F1 B7F4
Lillenthal, David E. B6F4
Lincoln, Abraham B7F4
Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot B7F1
Lumumba, Patrice B6F1
MacMillan, Harold B7F1
Marshall, Thurgood B9F4
McCarthy, Joseph B1F1 B5F1 B8F6
Meany, George B2F5
Meyner, Robert B1F1-B1F2 B2F1 B3F4 B6F3 B6F5 B8F2
Middle East B1F1 B5F1 B6F2-B6F3 B7F4 B9F1-B9F6
Mikoyan, Anastas B2F1
Nagy, Imre B2F1
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B1F1 B7F4-B7F5 B9F1
NATO B7F3
Nazism B5F4
Nehru, Jawaharlal B1F3 B3F2 B8F5
New Jersey B1F1-B1F2 B2F1 B2F5-B3F4 B4F4 B4F6-B5F3 B5F5-B5F6 B6F2-B6F3 B6F5 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1-B8F2 B8F4-B8F6
New York B4F6 B6F5 B7F1-B7F2 B8F5
New York City B5F3 B7F2 B8F6
Nixon, Richard M. B1F1 B1F3 B2F1-B2F2 B2F4 B3F1-B3F3 B4F3 B4F5-B5F1 B5F4-B5F6 B6F4 B7F1-B7F3 B8F1 B8F4-B8F5 B8F7
Norway B3F3
nuclear weapons B1F1 B1F3 B4F1-B4F2 B4F6-B5F3 B5F6-B6F1 B7F4 B8F5 B9F1 B9F4-B9F5 B9F8
Oman B8F3
Organization of American States B5F2 B6F4
organized crime B2F1 B2F5 B4F3 B7F1-B7F2
payola B8F5
peace B1F2-B1F3 B2F2 B2F5 B3F3 B4F2 B5F1 B5F3-B5F4 B6F1 B6F3 B7F1 B7F3-B7F4 B9F4 B9F6 B9F8
Pentagon B8F1
Poland B8F5
police B1F3 B9F2
polio B7F3
Powell, Adam Clayton B9F2-B9F3
Powers, Francis B7F1
Pravda B4F6
prayer B1F2
press B2F1 B4F1 B6F2
prices and wages B9F3 B9F5
Queen Elizabeth II B1F4
quiz shows B5F1
racial violence B6F3
Trujillo, Rafael B5F1
Rayburn, Sam B4F5
Republican Party B1F2 B2F1 B2F4 B3F1 B3F4-B4F1 B5F2 B5F4-B5F5 B6F1-B6F4 B7F1-B7F2 B7F4 B8F1 B8F5 B9F2-B9F3 B9F8
riots B9F2
Rockefeller, Nelson B1F3 B2F1 B3F1-B3F3 B4F3 B4F5-B4F6 B5F4-B5F5 B6F2 B6F4-B7F3 B8F1 B8F5 B9F3 B9F8
Romney, George W. B9F2 B9F6-B9F8
Rusk, Dean B5F3
Russia B1F3 B2F1 B2F3-B3F1 B3F3 B4F1-B4F2 B4F6 B5F3 B5F6 B6F2 B6F5 B7F3-B7F4 B8F5 B9F7
science B1F2 B5F6
Sihanduk, Prince B9F8
slums B4F1
smoking B9F2
socialized medicine B6F4
South Africa B1F1 B3F1
South America B6F5 B8F7-B9F1
South Korea B7F4
Soviet Union B1F3 B2F2 B3F3 B4F1-B4F2 B4F6 B5F6 B6F2 B6F5 B7F4 B8F4 B8F7 B9F2 B9F4 B9F6
space exploration B1F2 B2F2 B2F5 B3F2 B3F4 B4F2-B4F3 B4F6-B5F1 B5F4 B6F3-B6F5 B7F4 B8F4 B9F1-B9F2 B9F5
sports B4F3 B7F5 B8F4
Stalin, Joseph B2F2 B3F1 B3F3 B6F2
Stalinism B1F4
Stassen, Harold B8F5
states rights B5F4
steel industry B1F4 B3F1-B3F2 B5F3 B6F5 B7F2-B7F3 B8F5
Stevenson, Adlai E. B1F1-B1F4 B3F2 B4F3 B5F4-B5F5 B6F4 B7F3-B7F4 B8F1
strikes B2F2 B3F1 B3F3 B5F6 B6F5 B7F2-B7F3 B8F5 B9F1 B9F5
students B2F1 B3F2 B5F3 B8F5
Suez Canal B4F6
Supreme Court B7F3 B9F3
Symington, Stuart B1F1 B3F2 B5F5 B7F3
Syria B7F5
Taft Hartley Act B6F4-B6F5 B7F2
Taft, Robert B2F1 B2F5 B6F1
Taiwan B9F6
tariffs B1F3 B2F4 B3F4
taxes B1F1-B1F2 B2F4 B3F1 B3F3-B3F4 B4F4 B4F6 B5F1 B5F4-B5F5 B6F5 B7F2-B7F4 B8F5 B9F5 B9F7
teachers B9F1
Teamsters B1F2-B1F3 B2F5 B4F5-B4F6 B8F4
television B6F5 B8F5
time saving B3F2
Tito, Josip Broz B2F5
trade B9F7
transit B5F3 B7F2 B8F6
trucking industry B3F1
Truman, Bess B2F1
Truman, Harry S. B1F1-B1F2 B2F1 B3F4-B4F1 B4F3 B4F5 B5F4-B5F5 B6F1-B6F2 B7F1 B7F4 B8F4-B8F5
Turkey B1F2
U.S. Constitution B2F3 B9F3
U.S. dollar B4F2
U.S. Mail B9F6
Ulbricht, Walter B7F2
unemployment B3F3-B3F4 B4F6 B6F1 B9F5
unions B1F3-B1F4 B3F2 B5F3 B6F4 B7F2 B8F5 B9F1
United Arab Republic B7F5
United Auto Workers B6F4 B7F4
United Nations B1F1-B1F3 B2F2 B2F5-B3F1 B4F1 B4F6-B5F3 B5F6-B6F1 B6F4-B7F1 B7F4 B8F2 B8F4 B9F1 B9F4 B9F6
urban voters B5F5 B7F4
Vietnam War B9F1-B9F8
violence B9F6
Vishinsky, Andrey B1F1 B2F2
voting B1F3-B2F1 B4F1-B4F2 B5F1 B5F5 B6F5 B8F1 B8F4-B8F6
Wallace, George B9F2
War on Poverty B9F1 B9F6
Warsaw Pact B6F4
weather B1F1 B7F2-B7F3 B8F6
West Virginia B1F1
Wilson, Harold B9F2
Zarubin, Vasily B4F6
Zedong, Mao B2F5 B3F3 B8F4 B8F6 B9F2-B9F4 B9F6-B9F7
Zhukov, Georgy B5F5 B6F4